<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Blog on An Do</title>
        <link>https://andrewdo25.github.io/categories/blog/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Blog on An Do</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://andrewdo25.github.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Cà phê thế nào là ngon?</title>
        <link>https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/ca-phe-the-nao-la-ngon/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 19:10:13 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/ca-phe-the-nao-la-ngon/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/ca-phe-the-nao-la-ngon/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Cà phê thế nào là ngon?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chắc hẳn nhiều người cũng như mình, cà phê không chỉ là đồ uống, cà phê trở thành một phần không thể thiếu trong cuộc sống thường ngày. Vậy cà phê như thế nào là ngon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/ca-phe-the-nao-la-ngon/image_1.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2160&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/ca-phe-the-nao-la-ngon/image_1_hu2ac3dcbd9ca4c0b8ac1553f57374415c_425394_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/ca-phe-the-nao-la-ngon/image_1_hu2ac3dcbd9ca4c0b8ac1553f57374415c_425394_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Cà phê như thế nào là ngon?&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sáng nay mình có lướt một vòng Facebook, tình cờ đọc được topic một số anh em tranh luận về chủ đề cà phê ngon. Người thì nói cà phê là phải đắng, uống vào sốc tinh thần tỉnh táo ngay. Người thì bảo cà phê phải có vị hơi chua của Arabica, hậu vị phải ngọt của cà phê chế biến ướt đặc sản. Lại có kẻ vô chửi bới nói các anh lạc hậu, giờ người ta phải uống cold brew mới là hợp thời đại. Vậy theo mọi người, ý kiến nào đúng?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theo suy nghĩ của riêng mình, uống cà phê là một cách để bổ sung năng lượng cho thể xác và cả tinh thần.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Về thể xác, chỉ cần cà phê nguyên chất, không pha trộn các loại hoá chất độc hại, cà phê không rõ nguồn gốc, tóm lại là không ảnh hưởng xấu tới sức khoẻ là ok. Mỗi ngày uống 1 tách cà phê rất tốt cho trí não và sức khỏe. Thời điểm tốt nhất để uống một tách cà phê để lượng caffeine đạt đỉnh mỗi ngày là từ 9h30 đến 11h30 sáng. Lý do là bởi caffeine tương tác với một nội tiết tố chủ đạo trong cơ thể có tên là Cortisol giúp điều hòa đồng hồ sinh học và thúc đẩy sự tỉnh táo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mặt thứ hai là về tinh thần, đã là tinh thần thì không ai cân đo, không dùng chỉ số để kiểm đếm được, chỉ cần bản thân cảm thấy thoải mái, sảng khoái xuyên suốt một ngày làm việc tức là cà phê đó ngon. Ngoài việc nghiện công nghệ, có lẽ thứ mình nghiện tiếp theo đó chính là cà phê. Những buổi sáng tinh mơ mớ ngủ sau khi thức đêm cùng cái máy tính, thứ chúng ta nghĩ đến có lẽ là cà phê. Giữa nhịp sống hối hả và guồng quay bất tận của công việc, không gì tuyệt vời hơn giây phút thư giãn cùng bạn bè và những người thân yêu, chia sẻ những buồn vui và cùng nhau thưởng thức những ly cà phê.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Có lẽ bạn không tin, nhưng sự thực rằng, cà phê giúp bản thân mình có thêm nguồn năng lượng mới. Giúp mình giữ vững được tinh thần năng động và nhiệt huyết. Giống với nhà soạn nhạc vĩ đại người Đức Johann Sebastian Bach, có thể diễn tả như sau: “Without my morning coffee, I’m just like a dried-up piece of roast goat”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/ca-phe-the-nao-la-ngon/image_2.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2160&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/ca-phe-the-nao-la-ngon/image_2_huefb0a983bbcb9fb97ef6578366cf1ec4_418750_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/ca-phe-the-nao-la-ngon/image_2_huefb0a983bbcb9fb97ef6578366cf1ec4_418750_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Hãy tận hưởng trọn vẹn ly cà phê của mình&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mỗi người có một cuộc sống khác nhau, trải nghiệm khác nhau và tâm hồn khác nhau, lỡ như gu cà phê có không hợp nhau thì đó cũng là điều dễ hiểu. Cái khẩu vị ngon của người này không thể là chuẩn mực của người khác được, nên tranh luận là vô nghĩa. Thay vì chê bai ly cà phê của người khác, hãy tận hưởng trọn vẹn ly cà phê của mình nhé!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What this blog is all about?</title>
        <link>https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/what-this-blog-is-all-about/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 14:50:51 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/what-this-blog-is-all-about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://andrewdo25.github.io/p/what-this-blog-is-all-about/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What this blog is all about?" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;some-first-words&#34;&gt;Some first words
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sweet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, my blog, is a storybook of mine that is about all aspects of my life, and knowledge I learned in a life of living (I’m not sure about that, my life is quite boring). I am a data scientist. I am excited to share my experiences and insights with you about data science, artificial intelligence, and other topics that interest me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why did I name my site “Sweet”?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good question. I don’t know, too. I feel it is catchy 😎😎. I am not sure if I will keep it or not, but for now, it is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to AI and Data Science, there is always something new to learn. It&amp;rsquo;s a field that is constantly evolving, and I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to be a part of it. As a data scientist, my job involves collecting, analyzing, and interpreting large amounts of data to solve complex problems. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by the power of data and the insights that can be gleaned from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more to life than just work, and I believe in enjoying the journey as much as reaching the destination. That&amp;rsquo;s why I plan to share some personal stories on this blog, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So blogging is not the main target of this site. I have a bad memory, so writing things down is the best way to store them, and maybe it could be helpful for some people. I will mainly talk about everything in my development path.  It can be covered from casual stories when coding, some tips, hacks, and everything I learn and share with you. I want this to be a space where you can come to learn and grow, just like I am. From technical tutorials to casual stories, there will be a little bit of everything here. I believe that knowledge is power, and I want to help you unlock your full potential. I will dive deeper into the topic in the below &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#topics-i-plan-to-cover&#34; &gt;section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site includes 3 parts: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://andrewdo25.github.io/categories/guideline/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://andrewdo25.github.io/categories/blog/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Blogs&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://andrewdo25.github.io/categories/project/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline&lt;/strong&gt;: My how-to on almost everything in development and life. From tips on how to live a better life to coding hacks, I will share everything I know and help you improve in all areas of your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog&lt;/strong&gt;: As its name suggests, it is about my personal stories. I will share my experiences and lessons learned in a fun and engaging way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project&lt;/strong&gt;: That’s the main one. In addition to blogging, I also have a strong passion for projects. I will document my projects here so that you can get a full overview of the process and dive into the details if you&amp;rsquo;re interested. I hope that these projects will inspire you and give you some ideas for your work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really want to document everything, so that if someone wants to learn, or I when forget, can go to the site, read the blog, do some practice with it, and we could save a lot of time. My documenting skill is not so good, so if there are some typos or misleading information, leave a comment in the comment section, or contact me so I can fix it as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;topics-i-plan-to-cover&#34;&gt;Topics I plan to cover
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am a Data Scientist, so obviously my main posts will be around AI and Data Science. Below are the topics that interest me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-science&#34;&gt;Data Science
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data science is a vast field that involves the use of statistical and computational methods to extract insights and knowledge from data. In my blog, I plan to share some of the tools and techniques I use to analyze data and build predictive models. What I share can also be the difference when we work with real data compared to when we use published data sets when studying and researching. Some of the challenges I faced and how I overcame them, or maybe some other interesting things such as some questions during the Data Scientist interview for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;artificial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Artificial Intelligence
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am also interested in Artificial Intelligence (AI), so I will talk about some AI topics, such as computer vision, natural language processing, and some other related topics. Artificial Intelligence (AI) is one of the most exciting and rapidly evolving fields in technology today. AI has the potential to transform the way we live and work, and I will share my insights into some of the latest breakthroughs in AI research and their potential applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-topics&#34;&gt;Other topics
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I wrote this post, I only planned to talk about the above, but as I say, it is not flexible, and I will write down everything as long as I know about it. So stay focused, and ask me if you want to know something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I can talk about books, materials, coffee, some helpful links, and other things that help people. If you have something want to share with me, please let me know in the comment or contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to share this journey with you. Here is my post about the aim of this blog. I do not expect much about that, but I hope it could help someone in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or comments, feel free to leave them in the comments section or contact me directly. Thank you for reading, and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to share more with you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to bring joy and inspiration to your day. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
